# JAVIER RAMIREZ

Software Engineer

0033770407936

javier.ramirez.leiva0@gmail.com

https://fr.linkedin.com/in/javier-ramirez-leiva-681909124

Lyon, France

https://javier-ramirez-leiva.github.io/



Passionate software engineer dedicated to making a positive impact. With a global perspective gained from experiences in France and Spain, I have diverse expertise spanning CAD, automotive industry, security, and IoT. Presently employed at Dassault Systèmes in Lyon, France.

# EXPERIENCE

#### **Dassault Systemes / Software Engineer**

08/2019-Present

Electrical System Design app inside the CATIA portfolio of the 3DExperience platform from Dassault Systemes.

- C++ development for CAD and PLM applications to design electrical systems on Windows and Linux OS
- CI/CD processes and enhance workflow efficiency through the development of tools using Python and Bash scripting
- Develop UI elements utilizing web technologies to improve the user interface and overall user experience
- Draft detailed technical software specifications and plan strategies for unit testing
- · Design software architecture with a primary focus on reusability, modular frameworks and enhanced flexibility
- Define models for Model-Based Systems Engineering (MBSE) to contribute to the engineering process

#### **Continental / Software Engineer**

01/2017-08/2019

AKKA Technologies on behalf of Continental Automotive France SAS. ECU software development to control a Direct Injection Engine inside the new E-Power technology for Nissan.

- Design of the system architecture for a real-time application. Focus on software reliability
- Software development on C/C++ code conforming the AUTOSAR standard
- Python and Perl scripting to automate the creation of tests for both validation and non-regression purposes
- Team management, AKKA for Continental. Technical guidance and support to fellow employees
- Develop a structured workflow for the internal code review process, supported by an automated system

# Rockwell Collins / Software Engineering Intern

03/2016-09/2016

Security application to control cameras using the detections made by the radar FMWC PSR-500

- C++ development using the QT framework for Windows and Linux OS
- Plan and specify validation tests to ensure the quality and reliability of software
- Create software mock-ups tailored for customer demonstrations.

# EDUCATION

#### Master of Engineering. Electrical and Electronic engineering

ENSEEIHT (Ecole Nationale Supérieure d'Electrotechnique, d'Electronique, d'Informatique, d'Hydraulique et des Télécommunications) 2015 - 2016

## Master of Engineering. Electrical and Electronic engineering

UPNA (Universidad Publica de Navarra) 2014 - 2015

## **Engineering degree. Electronic engineering**

Universidad de La Rioja 2010 - 2014

## SKILLS

<b>Programming Languages</b>	<b>Software Applications</b>	Technologies	Development Methods
C, C++ (C++ 11)	Visual Studio, QT IDE, Eclipse	Embedded systems	V Cycle, Agile
Python (3.0), Bash, Perl, VBS	Git, CMake	CAD, System Engineering	Object Oriented Programming, design Patterns, TDD
HTML, Javascript, CSS	CATIA, 3D Experience, Matlab	Real-Time, Multicore, AUTOSAR	CI/CD, Unit Testing, Automatic Testing

## LANGUAGES

Spanish(Native)

• English(Full professional proficienty)

French(Full professional proficienty)